KARA EVANS

kara.e177409@gmail.com · <u>LinkedIn</u> · <u>Portfolio</u> Cleveland, Ohio | *Open to hybrid & remote roles*.

SUMMARY

Data analyst with over eight years of biomedical industry experience analyzing laboratory data and applying effective problem-solving skills. Managed departmental deviation reports and reduced report backlog by 20% within the first year of assignment. Improved and maintained laboratory inventory program, saving company time and money. An adaptable, fast learner who has trained and educated other employees in each professional role.

Skills: SQL, Tableau, Python, Statistical Analysis

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Optometric Technician, Dr. Jodi Rowson & Associates | January 2023-present

- Record patient data and schedule appointments using electronic health record system.
- Communicate with insurance companies to obtain patient eligibility information.

Senior Laboratory Technologist, Cleveland Cord Blood Center | November 2017-December 2022

- Evaluated risk of unexpected outcomes, performed investigations, and submitted detailed investigative reports each week, exceeding goal for report submissions by 400%.
- Maintained detailed inventory records to track supply counts, product information, and expiration dates.

Laboratory Technician, Cleveland Clinic | September 2015-November 2017

- Recorded patient data and maintained specimen tracking information using laboratory information management system.
- Resolved problems involving patient samples and communicated updates to hospital staff in a timely manner.

Analyst, CWM Environmental | August 2014-September 2015

• Performed environmental analysis on industrial waste samples within client-specific deadlines.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Biological Sciences, Certificate in Environmental Studies, Ohio University | May 2014

PROJECTS

Staffing Allocation Plan

Performed data cleansing and integration techniques on multiple data sets to assist a staffing agency with distributing medical staff throughout the United States. Examined trends using statistical analyses and visualizations in Tableau. Developed a dashboard to illustrate areas most affected by influenza infections and in need of additional staff.

Product Analysis

Evaluated movie rental company data to provide insights prior to the launch of a new video streaming service. Organized and joined data tables in SQL using queries and common table expressions to answer complex business questions. Built visualizations in Tableau. Findings include geographical sales data, customer behavior, and film rental performance.

Customer Analysis

Conducted exploratory analyses on customer data from an online grocery store to understand customer demographics and behavior. Merged data frames and developed new variables using Python to answer stakeholder questions. Generated visualizations to illustrate relationships between variables. Findings include ideal advertising times and popular products.